Guide to the New York City Department of Traffic Parking Lot Photographs and Related Publications 1949-1988 PR 451
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Photographs, 1958-1979
  - Subseries I.E. Photographs: Queens, 1958-1979
    - [Jamaica No. 2 Field], undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
      Views of Jamaica No. 2 Field, on the block bounded by 90th and 91st Avenues, 168th and 169th Streets, Queens.
    - [Jamaica No. 4 Field] (folder 1 of 2), undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
      Original folder labeled "Jamaica." Contains views of the Jamaica Theatre (155-16 Jamaica Avenue) and vicinity, as well as Jamaica No. 4 Field, at 90th Avenue between Parsons Boulevard and 160th Street, Queens.
    - [Jamaica No. 4 Field] (folder 2 of 2), 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
      Original folder labeled "Jamaica #4 Photographs." Contains construction views of Jamaica No. 4 Field, at 90th Avenue between Parsons Boulevard and 160th Street, Queens.
    - [Jamaica No. 5 Parking Deck] (folder 1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
      Original folder labeled "Jamaica #5." Contains construction photographs of the municipal parking lot at 168th Street and 93rd Avenue.
    - [Jamaica No. 5 Parking Deck] (folder 2 of 2), 1970 May 8 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
      Original folder labeled "Garage—Jamaica #5 169th St. & Archer." Contains views of traffic/transit officials at the completed facility at 168th Street and 93rd Avenue, Queens.
    - [Jamaica No. 6 Garage], 1972 March-September (Offsite-box 2, Folder 19)
      Original folder labeled "Jamaica 6." Contains construction photographs of Jamaica No. 6 Garage, at Archer Avenue and 165th Street, Queens.
    - [Jamaica No. 7 Field], 1967 June 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 20)
      Original folder labeled "Jam Ave & 163 St Qns | 6/16/67 | Jam 7." Contains views of a parking field and proposed structure on the block bounded by 89th Avenue, 162nd Street, Jamaica Avenue, and 163rd Street, Queens.
    - [Queens Plaza Garage] (folder 1 of 2), 1971, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
      Original folder labeled "Queens Plaza Garage. Pictures. TF 446." Contains views of the construction of the Queens Plaza Garage, located on Bridge Plaza South between 28th Street and Jackson Avenue, Queens.
    - [Queens Plaza Garage] (folder 2 of 2), 1971, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 22)
    - [Queens Village Field], 1973 June 5 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 23)
      Original folder labeled "Queens Village (Operation Main Street) Pictures." Contains views of Jamaica Avenue and 218th Street, site of the Queens Village Field, 218-02 Jamaica Avenue, Queens.
    - [Rego Park No. 1 Field], [1962] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
      Views of Rego Park No. 1 Field between 57th and 59th Avenues, 92nd and 94th Streets, Queens. One published in the City of New York, Department of Traffic Annual Report, 1962 (see Box 3, Folder 4).
    - [Rego Park No. 2 Field], [1962] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 25)
      A view of Rego Park No. 2 Field, between 92nd and 94th Streets, 59th Avenue, and the Long Island Expressway, Queens. One published in the City of New York, Department of Traffic Annual Report, 1962 (see Box 3, Folder 4).
    - [Roosevelt Avenue & Main Street], 1970 June 15 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
      Original folder labeled "Roosevelt & Main." Contains views of the intersection of Roosevelt Avenue and Main Street, Queens.
    - [Rosedale Field], 1965 March 12 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
      Original folder labeled "Rosedale - Pictures." Contains views of the site of the future Rosedale Field at the Rosedale Station of the Long Island Rail Road (Francis Lewis Boulevard between Sunrise Highway and North Conduit Boulevard):
      (1) From L.I.R.R. at Francis Lewis Boulevard
      (2) Looking east at Francis Lewis Boulevard
      (3) Looking west at Francis Lewis Boulevard
      (4) Looking east at Brookville Boulevard
      (5) Looking west from Hook Creek Boulevard
    - [Van Wyck Expressway], 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
      Original folder labeled "Van Wyck—Various Merges." Contains views of traffic near entrance and exit ramps on the Van Wyck Expressway, photographed September 11 and 15, 1969, and May 11, 1970.
  - Subseries I.F. Photographs: Staten Island, 1962-1963
    - [Great Kills Field], undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
      Views of the proposed site of Great Kills Field, 3928 Amboy Road, near Hillside Terrace, Staten Island.
    - [New Dorp Fields], 1963 September 23, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
      Views of the proposed sites of three municipal parking fields
      (1) New Dorp No. 1 (New Dorp Lane between 4th Street and New Dorp Plaza)
      (2) New Dorp No. 2 (New Dorp Lane at 9th Street)
      (3) New Dorp No. 3 (along South Railroad Avenue?)
    - [Port Richmond No. 1 Field], undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 31)
      Views of Port Richmond No. 1 Field, at the intersection of Maple and Grove Avenues, Staten Island.
    - [Port Richmond Avenue Shopping District], [before 1963] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
      Views of traffic and parking conditions in the vicinity of Port Richmond Avenue, Post Avenue, and Heberton Avenue, Staten Island.
    - [St. George Field], [1962] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 33)
      Views of St. George Field, at Hyatt Street, between Central Avenue and St. Mark's Place. One photograph shows the 1864 Brighton Heights Reformed Church (320 St. Mark's Place), which was destroyed by fire in 1996. One view published in the City of New York, Department of Traffic Annual Report, 1962 (see Box 3, Folder 4).
    - [Stapleton No. 1 Field], undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
      Views of the proposed site of Stapleton No. 1 Field, between Prospect and Cross Streets, and Bay Street and railroad right-of-way, Staten Island.
    - [Stapleton No. 2 Field], 1963 September 23 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
      Views of the proposed site of Stapleton No. 2 Field, Staten Island.
- Series II. Publications, 1949-1988
  Approximately ninety publications, some issued by the Department of Traffic, others by related New York City and State agencies, supplementing the locations documented in the photographs of Series I.
  Series II is organized in six subseries. Files within each subseries are listed chronologically.
  Subseries II.A.
  Publications: New York City-wide and regional, 1949-1988
  Subseries II.B.
  Publications: Bronx, 1968, 1983
  Subseries II.C.
  Publications: Brooklyn, 1966-1983
  Subseries II.D.
  Publications: Manhattan, 1955-1984
  Subseries II.E.
  Publications: Queens, circa 1962-1983
  Subseries II.F.
  Publications: Staten Island, 1983
  - Subseries II.A. Publications: New York City-wide and regional, 1949-1988
    - New York City Charter (2 volumes), 1949, 1969 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
      As amended to March 15, 1949 and January 1, 1969.
    - Traffic Commission Report (City of New York), 1949 May 1, December 31 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
    - City of New York. Department of Traffic. Annual Report (7 folders), 1954, 1962-1967 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3-9)
      Box 3, Folder 3: 1954
      Box 3, Folder 4: 1962 (2 copies; copy 2 defective)
      Box 3, Folder 5: 1963 (2 copies)
      Box 3, Folder 6: 1964
      Box 3, Folder 7: 1965 (2 copies)
      Box 3, Folder 8: 1966
      Box 3, Folder 9: 1967
    - Joint Study of Arterial Facilities, New York - New Jersey Metropolitan Area (Port of New York Authority / Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority), 1955 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 10)
    - Department of City Planning Bulletin, 1955 December (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36 (oversize))
      With two maps dated December 1955:
      (1) "Conversion Districts, Department of City Planning, City of New York."
      (2) "Total Workers in New York City by Conversion Districts, [in] 1950."
    - Subway Schedules 2A, 1959 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37 (oversize))
    - New York City Department of Traffic letterhead reproductions, [1962-1968] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 38 (oversize))
    - Meet Our People Presents Personnel Awarded Certificates of Service, New York City Department of Traffic, circa 1963 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
    - Traffic Report, Metropolitan New York Area (Highway Transportation Studies Group), 1964 August (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
    - Metropolitan Mobility: Proposals for Improved Transportation to Serve New York City (City Planning Commission), 1965 November 15 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13)
    - Regional Plan News, number 82, 1966 February (Offsite-box 3, Folder 14)
      Lead article: "Transportation and the Manhattan Central Business District: A Regional Plan Association Policy Statement."
    - Municipal Engineers Journal, vol. 53, fourth quarterly issue (2 copies), 1967 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - Community Planning Districts: Boundaries and Procedures for Modification (City Planning Commission), 1968 March (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - Traffic Regulations Established by the Commissioner of Traffic Under Authority of Chapter 40 of the New York City Charter (City of New York. Department of Traffic), 1968 August 1 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
    - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission. Regional Profile, vol. 2, no. 1, "1970 Population Traits", 1973 January (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
    - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission. Regional Profile, vol. 2, no. 3, "1970 Automobile Availability", 1973 March (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
    - Tri-State Regional Planning Commission. Regional Profile, vol. 2, no. 4, "1970 workplaces and Work Travel", 1973 May (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
    - Metro New York: An Economic Perspective, 1974 March 18 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 21)
    - Plazas for People (City of New York. Department of City Planning), 1976 September (Offsite-box 3, Folder 22)
    - Center City Environment and Transportation: Local Government Solutions, 1977 December (Offsite-box 3, Folder 23)
    - You and your community board (League of Women Voters), 1978 March 8 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 24)
      With
      (1) "Lend a Hand in Your Community Board" (after November 1975).
      (2) "Directory [of] New York City Community Board Offices" (revised July 10, 1979).
    - Regional Recovery: The Business of the Eighties (Port Authority of NY & NJ. Committee on the Future), 1979 June 1 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 25)
    - Fund for the City of New York. Three-Year Report (2 copies), 1979-1981 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 26)
    - Fund for the City of New York. Three-Year Report, 1982-1984 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 27)
    - New York Affairs, vol. 7, no. 3, "The Transit Issue", 1982 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 28)
    - Message of the Mayor (City of New York. Executive Budget. Fiscal Year 1983), 1982 May 10 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 29)
    - First Annual Conference on New York City Public Transit, 1982 December 16 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 30)
    - City Streets: A Report on Policies and Programs (New York City Department of Transportation) (3 copies in 3 folders), 1983 July (Offsite-box 3, Folder 31-33)
    - The Regional Economy: 1984 Review, 1985 Outlook for the New York-New Jersey Metropolitan Region (Port Authority of NY & NJ), 1985 March (Offsite-box 3, Folder 34)
    - The Economic Impact of the Port Industry on the New York-New Jersey Metropolitan Region (Port Authority of NY & NJ), 1985 April (Offsite-box 3, Folder 35)
    - Port Authority of NY & NJ Annual Report 1984, 1985 April 11 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 36)
    - An Approach to Reducing Vehicle Congestion in New York City, 1986 September 10 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 37)
    - City of New York. Department of Transportation. Safety Division. Biennial Report, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 38)
    - New York City Department of Transportation. Bureau of Traffic. Annual Report, 1987 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 39)
    - New York City Department of Transportation. Annual Report, 1987, 1988 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
    - The Region / 1988 (Regional Plan Association Annual Report) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
  - Subseries II.B. Publications: Bronx, 1968, 1983
    - Concourse Action Program [prospectus], [1968] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 39 (oversize))
    - Concourse Action Program: An Interim Report to the Community (Housing and Development Administration. Office of Bronx Borough President), 1968 June (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    - Statement of Community District Needs, Fiscal Year 1985: Bronx, 1983 August (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II.C. Publications: Brooklyn, 1966-1983
    - Erasmus Gardens, 1966 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 40 (oversize))
    - Cross Brooklyn Expressway: A Limited-Access State-Federal-Aided Highway with Multiple Benefits for the Residents of Brooklyn and the City of New York, 1967 January 18 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    - Downtown Brooklyn... A Reconnaissance, 1969 January (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn College Master Plan 1975, 1969 June (Offsite-box 2, Folder 41 (oversize))
    - Brooklyn Center, [1970-1973] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
    - Fulton Arcade (Office of Downtown Brooklyn Development), 1973 December (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
    - Statement of Community District Needs, Fiscal Year 1985: Brooklyn, 1983 August (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II.D. Publications: Manhattan, 1955-1984
    - A Parking Plan for the City of New York. Site 4: 8th Avenue and West 53rd Street, Borough of Manhattan, 1955 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - Parking Survey and Economic Study of the Bryant Park Area, New York, New York (H. K. Ferguson Company), 1957 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - Battery Park. Report to Mayor Wagner and the Board of Estimate by the Committee on Slum Clearance, 1959 January 19 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
    - Wide Support Backs Garage Plan for 15 Mid-Town Parking Sites, 1960 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
    - Lower Midtown Redevelopment, 2nd report (Skidmore, Owings & Merrill) (3 copies), 1961 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    - Report to the City of New York Department of Traffic on Traffic, Circulation and Related Studies in the New York Civic Center (Day & Zimmermann, Inc.), 1962 October 15 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13)
    - Traffic and Parking, Madison Square Garden Center, 1962 December (Offsite-box 4, Folder 14)
    - Gramercy Graphic, vol. 22, no. 6, 1963 September (Offsite-box 4, Folder 15)
      Contains article: "Citizens Are Debating Pros and Cons Of a Garage Under Madison Square."
    - Proposed Madison Square Garage. Feasibility Study, 1964 June (Offsite-box 4, Folder 16)
    - Study for an Underground Parking Garage in Madison Square Park, 1964 June 18 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 17)
    - A Proposal by the Department of Traffic for an Off-Street Parking Program in Mid-Town Manhattan, 1965 April 26 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 18)
    - Addition to Battery Parking Garage, Lower Manhattan (Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority) (2 copies), 1965 October 6 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 19)
    - Lower Manhattan Expressway Ad Hoc Coordinating Committee for Multi-Development Planning [typescript], 1967 December 15 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 20)
    - Preliminary Specification, New Police Headquarters & Public Garage, Manhattan Civic Center, 1967 December 29 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 42 (oversize))
    - Specifications for New Police Headquarters (PO-57) and Public Parking Garage (TR-423), [1968?] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 43 (oversize))
    - New Police Headquarters, Public Parking Garage, Pedestrian Plaza, 1968 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 44 (oversize))
    - Lincoln Square Community Action Planning Program, [1970 December] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 21)
    - Allen Street Redevelopment (City of New York. Department of City Planning. Urban Design Group), [1972] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 22)
    - Capital Project No. PW-244. Central Facilities to Supply Refrigeration for New York City Buildings in Manhattan Civic Center. Preliminary Presentation, 1972 April 6 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 23)
    - Lower Manhattan Development - 1972 (Office of Lower Manhattan Development), 1972 October (Offsite-box 4, Folder 24)
    - Chambers Street Study (Office of Lower Manhattan Development / Lower Manhattan Transportation Study Group), 1974 May 6 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 25)
    - Little Italy Risorgimento: Proposals for the restoration of an historic community (Department of City Planning), 1974 September (Offsite-box 4, Folder 26)
    - Midtown Development (City of New York. Department of City Planning), 1981 June (Offsite-box 4, Folder 27)
    - Decongesting Manhattan's Streets: A Report on Traffic Congestion in the Central Business District (Andrew Stein, Borough President), 1981 June 1 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 28)
    - Improved Transportation Between Midtown Passenger Terminals (Port Authority of NY & NJ), 1982 March (Offsite-box 4, Folder 29)
    - Statement of Community District Needs, Fiscal Year 1985: Manhattan, 1983 August (Offsite-box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ruben Rosario, "10M overhaul for cops' HQ. Building & plaza crumble 11 years after opening," New York Daily News, 1984 February 5 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 45 (oversize))
    - [Mutilated, partial report on traffic and pedestrians in Midtown Manhattan], undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 31)
  - Subseries II.E. Publications: Queens, circa 1962-1983
    - Improving the Long Island Expressway: A Plan to Improve Transportation and Relieve Traffic Congestion [photocopy], [1962-1965] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 32)
    - Queens Midtown Tunnel. Third Tube (Triborough Bridge and Tunnel Authority), 1965 December 29 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 33)
    - York College Master Plan 1975, 1970 November (Offsite-box 2, Folder 46 (oversize))
    - Jamaica Center (copy 1 of 2; with tipped in material), 1971 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 34)
    - Jamaica Center (copy 2 of 2), 1971 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 35)
    - [City of New York. Municipal Parking Garage. Queens, New York] (4 copies), [circa 1971-1975] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 36)
      Prospectus for the Queens Plaza Garage (scheduled to open Spring 1975), located on Bridge Plaza South between 28th Street and Jackson Avenue, Queens.
    - Far Rockaway Shopping Area, 1975 May (Offsite-box 4, Folder 37)
    - Jamaica Center Pedestrian Study (2 copies), 1976 November (Offsite-box 4, Folder 38-39)
    - A New Subway for Queens Plaza: Northern Boulevard Station-Route 131 A, 1979 August (Offsite-box 4, Folder 40)
    - Statement of Community District Needs, Fiscal Year 1985: Queens, 1983 August (Offsite-box 4, Folder 41)
  - Subseries II.F. Publications: Staten Island, 1983
    - Statement of Community District Needs, Fiscal Year 1985: Staten Island, 1983 August (Offsite-box 4, Folder 42)